Mahesh Dhaka

Looking for a Full Stack Developer position

Thunder Bay, ON maheshdhaka147@gmail.com +18073575247

Performance-driven Full Stack Developer with 5-years of experience in working on all phases of software development from designing to development. Diverse experience in web development, database management, software development, and machine learning. Willing to relocate anywhere within Canada.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

Moksha Folia - Remote August 2020 to Current

The company is a US-based startup that specializes in selling different types of plants online. As a Full Stack Developer, I am responsible for:

- Design and development of an eCommerce website using Shopify.
- Create a desktop-based application that manages the company's inventory.
- Development of application using Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Agile Methodology

Full Stack Developer

Webhobs - New Delhi, Delhi May 2015 to August 2019

As a Full Stack developer, I was responsible for front and backend web development. My job responsibility involved:

- Design and develop an e-commerce platform using best software development practices.
- Use object-oriented methodology and data structures to design efficient software.
- Demonstrable knowledge of front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, and JQuery.
- Advanced understanding of backend technologies such as Python, Node JS, Express JS.
- Design and develop an API from scratch by collaborating with stakeholders to meet business requirements.
- Design and develop reliable databases that meet performance requirements.

Education

Master's Degree in Computer Science

Lakehead University - Thunder Bay, ON September 2019 to April 2021

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Jaypee University - Solan, Himachal Pradesh

Skills

HTML (5 years)
Vanilla JavaScript (5 years)
React (3 years)
Node.js (5 years)
Express.js(5 years)

• jQuery (5 years) AJAX (5 years) XML (5 years) JSON (5 years)

• Python (5 years) PHP (2 years)

• MySQL (5 years) MongoDB (3 years)

• APIs (5 years) Git (5 years) GitHub (5 years)

• AWS (3 years) Devops (CI/CD) 3 years

• Docker (1 year)

Projects

- eCommerce Portal from Scratch: Developed an eCommerce portal from scratch for technology demonstration. The portal can be used by hosts to provide different types of experiences to the clients. It is similar to the Airbnb Experiences portal. The website does not use any frameworks and completely relies on core technologies such as HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, Python, PHP, and MySQL. The website also has its standalone messaging and billing portal. The complete website can be explored here
- Prediction of Correctly and Incorrectly Wore Masked Faces using Deep Learning: An increasing number of people are not following the face mask guidelines issued by authorities in wake of Covid-19. Some individuals do not put on the masks at all, while others do not cover their mouth, nose, or chin appropriately. The model detects individuals that are not wearing face masks appropriately using Convolution Neural Network (CNN). There was not any large dataset available for training the CNN model, so 3 different artificial datasets got prepared. The Project uses Python and Keras for the development.
- **Moksha Folia:** It is an eCommerce portal to sell various types of plants online. The website got developed using Shopify for the last Employer while working as a part-time Full Stack Developer. Complete functionality of the website can be <u>explored here</u>.
- **Webhobs Hosting Portal:** It is a Website Hosting and Domain Name service provider company. I worked for the organization for more than 4 years as a Full Stack Developer in a team of around 10 programmers. Some of the technologies used in the development are HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Python, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery, XML, JSON, APIs, AWS, and Docker. The website can be <u>explored here.</u>

Important Links

<u>Portfolio Website</u> <u>Current Leisure Project</u> <u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>